Guide to the Susan B. Anthony Papers, 1854-1905
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Susan B. Anthony Papers
1854-1905
Anthony, Susan B. (Susan Brownell), 1820-1906
0.4 cubic feet (1 box with 99 items)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Copies and some originals of correspondence to and from Susan B. Anthony, as well as a few autographed statements.
Biographical Note
Susan Brownell Anthony was born in Adams, Massachusetts on 15 February 1820. Her parents, Daniel Anthony and Lucy Read, raised her and her seven siblings as Quakers. After a series of financial setbacks and relocations, the Anthony family settled in Rochester, New York, where Susan B. Anthony became acquainted with many abolitionists and women's rights reformers of her day, including William Lloyd Garrison, Frederick Douglass, Amelia Bloomer, and Samuel May. In the early 1850s, she formed an alliance with Elizabeth Cady Stanton that was critical to the fight for woman suffrage.
In the late 1860s, Anthony published a radical periodical, The Revolution, and became executive director of the National Woman Suffrage Association. In 1892, two years after this organization had merged with the American Woman Suffrage Association, she became president of the combined organization, the National American Woman Suffrage Association. By the time Anthony died on 13 March 1906 in Rochester, New York, at the age of eighty-six, four states had granted women equal suffrage.
Scope and Content Note
The main concern of Anthony's letters from 1854-1866 was the antislavery movement. After the Civil War, she directed all her energy to the struggle for equal rights for women. Major Correspondents include Francis Jackson Garrison, William Lloyd Garrison, Samuel May, Eliza R. Whiting, and Elizabeth Cady Stanton. (Letters from Anthony to Stanton are located in Vassar's Stanton collection). Most letters are hand-written and have an accompanying transcript.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Alma Lutz Papers, Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries.
Elizabeth Cady Stanton Papers, Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Woman Suffrage and Women's Rights Collection, Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries.
The Papers of Elizabeth Cady Stanton and Susan B. Anthony. Microfilm. Wilmington, Del.: Scholarly Resources, c1991. 45 microfilm reels. VC microfilm no. 947.
Subject Headings
Names:
Garrison, Francis Jackson, 1848-1916; Garrison, William Lloyd, 1805-1879; May, Samuel, 1810-1899; Stanton, Elizabeth Cady, 1815-1902; Whiting, Eliza Rose Gray
Organizations:
National American Woman Suffrage Association; National Woman Suffrage Association (U.S.)
Subjects:
Slavery--Anti-slavery movements; Women's rights; Women--Suffrage; Women--Social conditions; Women social reformers; Abolitionists
Places:
United States--Social conditions; United States--Politics and government
VCL Categories:
Slavery and Antislavery; Women's History
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, November 2006. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, March 2023.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Alma Lutz, Vassar Class of 1912.
Series List
- Series I. Correspondence, 1854-1905
  - Letters from Susan B. Anthony
  - Letters to Susan B. Anthony
- Series II. Autographed Cards, 1872-1904
- Series III. Receipt, 1899
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence
  [except where noted, each item is hand-written and has an accompanying typed transcript]
  - Letters from Susan B. Anthony
    - Susan B. Anthony to Elizabeth Cady Stanton, 26 May 1856; (typed transcription only) (1.1)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Elizabeth Cady Stanton, 17 June [1856]; (typed transcription only) (1.2)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Elizabeth Cady Stanton, 25 Aug 1860; (typed transcription only) (1.3)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Elizabeth Cady Stanton, [Feb 1861]; (typed transcription only) (1.4)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Elizabeth Cady Stanton, 27 Feb 1862; (typed transcription only, Original in Stanton Scrapbook, Vol. 1) (1.5)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Betsey Voorhees, 28 June 1854 (1.6)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mr. [Samuel] May, 25 Dec 1855 (1.7)
    - Susan B. Anthony to William Lloyd Garrison, 8 Mar 1859 (1.8)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "My Dear Friend", 1 July 1863 (1.9)
    - Susan B. Anthony to [Samuel] May, 1 July 1863 (1.10)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mr. Crane, [186?] (1.11)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. Drake, 18 Sept 1863 (1.12)
    - Susan B. Anthony to [Samuel] May, 21 Sept 1863 (1.13)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Edmund G. Galin, 14 Dec 1863 (1.14)
    - Susan B. Anthony, E. Cady Stanton and Edwin A Studwell to Ludlow Patton, [1866] (1.15)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Miss Assing, 1 Mar 1866 (1.16)
    - Susan B. Anthony to A.E.R.A. Association, 9 Jan 1869 (1.17)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "Dear Sir", 4 Jan 1869; (no transcription) (1.18)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mr. Denton, 8 Feb 1869; (no transcription) (1.19)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "My Dear Friends", 30 Aug 1869 (1.20)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Redpath, 1 Jan 1870 (1.21)
    - Susan B. Anthony to T. B. Pugh, 9 Nov 1870 (1.22)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Man "Who Dares" (Redpath), 23 Dec 1870 (1.23)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. Oliver Bennett, 9 Feb 1871 (1.24)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mr. Grover, 9 Feb 1871 (1.25)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "Young Man", 19 Aug 1871 (1.26)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. Livermore, 28 Sept 1872 (1.27)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "Young Man", 19 Nov 1872 (1.28)
    - Susan B. Anthony to J. D. Buck, 22 Aug 1882 (1.29)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "Dear Sir", 12 Jan 1875 (1.30)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "Dear Sir", 8 Dec 1875 (1.31)
    - Susan B. Anthony to William Lloyd Garrison, 10 Feb 1876 (1.32)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "My Dear Friend", 18 July 1876 (1.33)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Thomas C. Powell, 22 Oct 1876 (1.34)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. Grey, 20 Nov 1880 (1.35)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. Blake, 7 Jan 1881 (1.36)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "Dear Friend", 9 Feb 1881 (1.37)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mr. Weinheimer, 5 May 1882 (1.38)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mr. Weinheimer, 26 May 1882 (1.39)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. Mellen, 5 Nov 1883 (1.40)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. Hutchins, 7 Jan 1884 (1.41)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "Dear Sir", 18 Jan 1884 (1.42)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. Blake, 21 Feb 1884 (1.43)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. Thomas, 22 Mar 1884 (1.44)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. Bowles, 21 Aug 1884; (no transcription) (1.45)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mr. Weinheimer, 21 July 1885 (1.46)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Frank, 11 Oct 1885 (1.47)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "My Dear Friend", 15 Oct 1885 (1.48)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Miss Boothe and Mrs. Wright, 7 Nov 1885 (1.49)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Scribners, 16 Feb 1886 (1.50)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Weinheimer, 24 June 1886 (1.51)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Wendell P. Garrison, 13 July 1887 (1.52)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Miss Booth, 22 Jan 1888 (1.53)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "My Dear Friend", 6 Feb 1888 (1.54)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "My Dear Friend", 11 Mar 1888 (1.55)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Grover Cleveland, 27 Mar 1888 (1.56)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "My Dear", 6 Apr 1888 (1.57)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "My Dear Friend", 1 Oct 1888 (1.58)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "My Dear Friend", 2 July 1889 (1.59)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. H. Hollway, 19 Aug 1889 (1.60)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Garrison Family, 2 Nov 1889 (1.61)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Francis J. Garrison, 7 Mar 1890 (1.62)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Francis J. Garrison, 11 Mar 1890 (1.62)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Francis J. Garrison, 6 April 1890 (1.62)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. Whiting, 4 Aug 1892 (1.63)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "My Dear Friend", 8 Dec 1892 (1.64)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "My Dear Friend", 1 Jan 1894 (1.65)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. Whiting, 2 Apr 1894; (TLS) (1.66)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Miss Hosmer, 21 Nov 1896 (1.67)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Maj. James B. Pond, 11 Jan 1897; (TLS) (1.68)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Frances Garrison, 5 Mar 1897; (TLS) (1.69)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Miss Miller, 23 Aug 1897 (1.70)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "Frank", 6 Feb 1899 (1.71)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "My Dear Friend", 6 Feb 1899 (1.72)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. J.P. Smith, 29 Mar 1900; (TLS) (1.73)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. Whiting, 25 May 1900 (1.74)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mr. Pond, 30 July 1900 (1.75)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. Whiting, 5 Mar 1901; (TLS) (1.76)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Nora (Stanton Barney), 24 Nov 1902; (TLS) (1.77)
    - Susan B. Anthony and Ida Husted Harper to Mr. Hamilton Holt, 1903; (TLS) (1.78)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. George Bass, 16 Jan 1904; (TLS) (1.79)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. George Bass, 1903; (TLS) (1.80)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Librarian, Vassar College, 31 Mar 1904; (TLS) (1.81)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Robert L. Stanton, 15 Apr 1904; (typed transcription only) (1.82)
    - Susan B. Anthony to "Dear Sirs", 15 Dec 1904 (1.83)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Barrows Brothers and Co., 14 Jan 1905 (1.84)
    - Susan B. Anthony to Miss C. Gallop, 3 May 1905; (TLS) (1.85)
    - Fragment of letter by Susan B. Anthony, undated (1.86)
    - Fragment of letter by Susan B. Anthony, undated; (TLS) (1.87)
  - Letters to Susan B. Anthony
    - Harriett Beecher Stowe to Susan B. Anthony, Dec 1869 (1.88)
    - Robert J. Burdette to Susan B. Anthony, 18 Mar 1903 (1.89)
    - Lillian M. N. Stevens to Susan B. Anthony, 13 Jan 1902; (TLS) (1.90)
- Series II: Autographed Cards
  - "A person, citizen, and voter…", 15 Nov 1872; (typed transcription only) (1.91)
  - "Let woman’s opinion be counted at the ballot box precisely as man's is!!", 18 Jan 1884 (1.92)
  - "Perfect equality of rights for women - civil and political - is the demand of the National Woman Suffrage Association...", 8 Sept 1889 (1.93)
  - Autographed slip for Birthday celebration, 15 Feb 1900 (1.94)
  - "Perfect equality of rights - civil and political - moral and social, industrial and educational - is the end of my effort", 24 May 1904 (1.95)
  - "Freedom to Women", undated (1.96)
- Series III. Receipt
  - Receipt for "Convention Expenses", 17 May 1899 (1.97)